ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers, 5780/203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series VI. Speeches
  - Puerto Rican Congress of New Jersey, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    Speech by Mazur, May 6
  - Puerto Rico Housing Dedication, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    Remarks by Mazur, April 13
  - Queens College (CUNY), 1994 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    Speech by Mazur honoring Sol Chaiken at the Center for Labor & Urban Analysis, Queens College of the City University of New York, June 6, 1992
  - Ramirez, Jose, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    See also subject files and speeches, FITTVCC Speech by Mazur honoring secretary general of Inter-American Federation of Textile, Garment, Leather and Shoe Workers, February 13, 1992
  - Retirees' Concert, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    Speech by Mazur at ILGWU retiree concert, November 1; outline for introductions of Mario Cuomo, Carl McCall, and Karen Burstein; full introduction of Cuomo
  - Retirees' Concert, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 35)
    See also Speeches – On the Mend Project 1993; see also Dinkins, David, NYC Mayoral Campaign (1) Speech by Mazur introducing NYC mayor David Dinkins at ILGWU retirees benefit concert for "On the Mend" project
  - Retirees' Concert, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    Remarks by Mazur at Town Hall concert, October 24
  - Sheinkman, Jack-American ORT, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 37)
    See also American ORT Speech by Mazur at tribute dinner for ACTWU president Sheinkman, May 16
  - Sheinkman, Jack-Cornell University, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 38)
    Speech by Mazur honoring Sheinkman at the dedication of an endowed professorship in his name, November 2
  - Sheinkman, Jack, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 39)
    See also Work in America Institute Draft of remarks by Mazur re ACTWU president Jack Sheinkman at awards ceremony by Work in America Institute, November 1992; remarks by Mazur at ACTWU convention re state of American labor, general economic and political prospects under Clinton, 1992
  - Social Democrats USA, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 40)
    See also subject file Speech by Mazur at testimonial dinner for Mazur, given the Eugene V. Debs Award by Social Democrats, June 10, 1987
  - South Africa, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 41)
    Greetings by Mazur welcoming John Coplyn of SACTWU (South Africa Clothing and Textile Workers Union?), January 12
  - Starobin, Herman-Keynesian Economics, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 42)
    See also Speeches – NAFTA 1991-1992; see also Democratic National Committee 1992 Paper, "Labor's Reaction to Keynesian Economic Policy," by Dr. Herman Starobin, director of research, ILGWU, at the Centennial Forum, Hofstra University, September 22-24
  - Stove, Furnance and Allied Applicance Workers, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 43)
    Remarks by Mazur at convention, re trade deficit, loss of manufacturing jobs, growing income gap, July 16
  - Sweatshops-Hofstra, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 44)
    Speech by Mazur, "Multinational Corporations and the Global Sweatshop in the 21st Century," delivered to the Hofstra University Symposium on International Competition and the Transnational Corporation, cosponsored by UAW District 65, January 23, 1988
  - Tax Proposal, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 45)
    Testimony by ILGWU president Sol Chaikin before the Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Representatives, opposing President Reagan's proposal to tax employer contributions to health insurance coverage and to fully tax unemployment compensation, eliminate deductibility of state and local taxes, and lower tax rate for wealthy, June 13, 1985
  - Trade and Jobs, 1988-1989 (Box 36, Folder 46)
    See also Textile & Apparel Trade Legislation; see also ITGLWF Fifth World Congress, Tokyo, September 26-30, 1988; see also NAFTA and Speeches – NAFTA Speech by Mazur, "The Effect of International Trade on Jobs," presented at A Dialogue on Social and Ethical Concerns in a Changing Economy, January 26, 1989; speech by Mazur to the ITGLWF Fifth World Congress, Tokyo, September 26-30, 1988
  - Trade and Workers' Rights, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 47)
    See also subject file Workers' Rights & Trade; see also Speeches – General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) 1993 Speech by Mazur to ITA (International Trade Group?) re trade and workers' rights; draft for Mazur by ILGWU international relations director Michele Briones, "Linking Trade to Workers' Rights: Developing Mechanisms to Enforce Internationally Agreed Standards on Workers Rights"
  - Trumka, Richard, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 48)
    Remarks of Richard L. Trumka, president, United Mine Workers of America, to the America Bar Association Labor and Employment Section luncheon, speaking as a coal miner and as an attorney, re national labor policy, August 7, 1990
  - Trumka, Richard-Workers Defense League, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 49)
    See also Speeches – Workers Defense League Remarks by Mazur at award presentation honoring Richard Trumka, May 13
  - Tyler, Gus, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 50)
    See also subject file Speech at Hofstra University upon receipt of honorary doctorate
  - Union Label and Service Trades Awards, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 51)
    Remarks by Mazur, May 11
  - United Hebrew Trades, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 52)
    Speech by Mazur at testimonial (centennial) luncheon, December 11, 1988
  - United Housing Foundation, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 53)
    See also subject file United Housing Foundation – National Housing Policy Forum 1992 Drafts of remarks to forum by Mazur
  - Vocational Training, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 54)
    See also Speeches – Labor and Human Resources Committee 1992; see also Speeches – Education Program Graduation Day 1988 Statement by Mazur as chair of the Consortium for Worker Education before the Assembly Committee on Skills Development and Vocational Education, January 27
  - Wages, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 55)
    See also Speeches – Labor Movement, Future of Testimony by Ray Marshall, chairman of the Commission on the Skills of the American Workforce, before the Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources, "America's Choice: High Skills or Low Wages," January 7, 1991; background material for Mazur speeches: poverty data from U.S. Census Bureau, with memo from ILGWU exec asst James Parrott and talking points, 1987; summary of State of Working America report re wages, income gap, purchasing power, 1988; NY Times clipping, "Rebuild America by Rebuilding Labor," by Ernest Lieberman, noting labor accounts for 10 percent of manufacturing costs but 75 percent of cuts, January 8, 1989; U.S. News & World Report clipping, "Labor's Agenda for the '90s" re efforts to stem decline in membership, March 19, 1990; clipping from the Economist re wages, July 7, 1990; handwritten notes by Mazur
  - Winpinsinger, William, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 56)
    Tribute message by Mazur on occasion of retirement of Winpisinger as president of International Association of Machinists, June 23, 1989; letter inviting Mazur to event, May 2, 1989
  - Zensen, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 57)
    See also subject files Zensen Opening remarks by Mazur at the eighth U.S.-Japan Joint Conference, December 12-14; talking points re 1994 congressional and state elections
  - Zensen, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 58)
    See also subject files Zensen Opening remarks by Mazur at the fifth joint conference, November 1987
- Series VII. ILGWU General Executive Board
  - GEB Executive Session (ACTWU/ILGWU Merger), February, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - ACTWU GEB Seating Arrangement, May 18, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - GEB Committee/Task Force, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - GEB Meeting (Tom Donahue Letter about Lane Kirkland), 1995 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - UNITE GEB Meeting, 6/31, David Melman Committee Task Force, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - GEB, December, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - ILGWU General Executive Board-Minutes of GEB Meetings September-October, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU General Executive Board (GEB), 1992-1995 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    Minutes, correspondence; inventory of documents on the Leather Workers' Union, c. 1995; memo from Irwin Solomon re Affiliates' Assistance Fund, handwritten memo re merger of Leather Workers, c. 1995
  - ILGWU General Executive Board, 1993-1994 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    Minutes; index of minutes for May and September 1993 meetings
  - ILGWU General Executive Board, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    Minutes, report of Dept. of Organizing and Field Services; GEB Report by Strike Preparation Task Force, January 15, 1991
  - ILGWU GEB Meeting, October, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    Agendas, memos, reports
  - ILGWU GEB Meeting, June, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - ILGWU General Executive Board-reports, Chicago, October, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    Highlights from regional reports excerpted by exec. asst. David Melman for Mazur; report to the General Executive Board by the Organization Dept.; report on finances of New Jersey Region, with plans for cost-cutting; report of Professional and Clerical Employees (PACE); report of Tennessee locals; report by general organizer Joe Danahy; list of education issues for Mazur's report; report of New England Region, including organizing activities and possible target shops; report of the Central States Region; Midwest Region; Southeast Region; Upper South Dept.; Philadelphia/South Jersey District Council; Northeast, Western Pennsylvania and Ohio Dept.; Local 132-98- 102; Local 23-25; Local 89-22-1; Puerto Rico District Council; report of Benefit 10Funds Dept.; Retiree Service Dept.; Health and Safety Dept.; Iernational Relations; Political Dept.
  - ILGWU GEB Meeting, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    Agendas, memos
  - ILGWU GEB Meeting, 1987-1990 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - ILGWU General Executive Board, Baltimore, MD, October, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    Agenda; reports by Benefit Funds Department and Department of Organization and Field Services; bylaws of Western Canadian Region; correspondence from Canadian manager; correspondence re drug testing
  - ILGWU GEB Meeting, June, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    Printed program, GEB Report to the 40th convention
  - ILGWU General Executive Board, Washington, DC, April, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    Agenda; minutes of eighth GEB meeting, Nov. 29 – Dec. 1, 1988, San Francisco, CA; reports of Health and Safety Department, Retiree Service Department, Department of Associate Membership, Social Services Task Force; report of financial status of Southwest District Council; report of Subcommittee on Workers' Compensation at the Union Health Center; GEB convention report re organizing; proposed constitutional amendments; testimony by Jay Mazur before the U.S. Dept. of Labor hearings in Industrial Homework in the Women's Apparel Industry, March 29, 1989; statement by AFL-CIO Executive Council on Industrial Homework, February 1989; related newspaper clippings; Justice, Chinese edition, February 1989; memo from organizer re flight of Chinatown contractors to Brooklyn to "escape" union, need to organize there; letter from Sen. Daniel Patrick Moynihan praising Chinatown Day Care Center; summary and full statement by Mazur opposing the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Expansion Act of 1989; memo re new GEB Organizing Subcommittee; memo from public relations consultant Ethan Geto (Geto & deMilly) re David Dinkins mayoral campaign strategy; Dinkins Daily newsletter; personal and confidential memo from ILGWU research director Herman Starobin to ACTWU president Jack Sheinkman as FFACT legislative committee chairman re report of a meeting with Pres. Bush, Republican senators, and industry representatives re imports; memo from vp Evelyn Dubrow re Senate minimum wage bill and letter to senators; valuation and review of ILGWU Staff Retirement Fund as of January 1, 1989; list of senators and congressmen invited to GEB reception; letter of invitation from Mazur
  - ILGWU General Executive Board, November, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    Agenda of 11/88 GEB meeting; minutes of the February 2, 1988, June 7, 1986, and November 1988 GEB meetings; Synopsis of the 1988 Gallup Study of Public Knowledge and Opinion Concerning the Labor Movement; Joint AFL-CIO/CTM (Confederation of Workers of Mexico) Statement, April 20, 1988; draft, AFL-CIO Ad Hoc Maquiladora Twin Plant Committee Textile/Apparel Industry Committee agenda; list of ILGWU vice presidents, weekly salaries, date of employment, date of birth, age at last birthday, November 4, 1988; list of ILGWU individual and local campaign contributors in 1988; letter from anonymous rank-and-file members, postmarked Johnstown, PA, complaining of poor representation by manager and business agent, November 14, 1988; letter to director of Staff Welfare Plan re raising life insurance program to conform with non-discrimination standards, November 18, 1988; report on contract negotiations, organizing activities, education and political activities, from Pacific Northwest District Council, November 14, 1988; confidential memo to Mazur from ILGWU researcher Herman Starobin re strategy on textile/apparel legislation, November 10, 1988; memo re status of negotiations with Jonathan Logan over proposed drug and alcohol abuse policy, November 19, 1988; statement of ILGWU drug and alcohol abuse policy for United Merchants and Manufacturers, October 31, 1988; press release, "Major Campaign Set to Bolster First-Ever VDT Health Safety Law," October 19, 1988; letters from district manager of Northern New England District Council complaining of preemption by union lawyer in negotiations with Malden Mills, March-May, 1987; letter re status of negotiations for Fall River contract extending 35-hour week, January 19, 1988; newspaper clippings
  - ILGWU General Executive Board (GEB), Unity House, June, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    Agenda, June 1988; Report by Mazur to board; memo from exec. Asst. James Parrott re suggested items to report; Report of the Union Label Department to the General Executive Board, 1988; Report of the Benefit Funds Department to the General Executive Board, June 20, 1988; PACE Professional and Clerical Employees Report to the General Executive Board, June 1988; Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry, Canada, by Research Dept., June 21, 1988
  - ILGWU General Executive Board, February, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    Decisions made at 10/87 GEB re staff changes (Susan Cowell elected to GEB, Susan Briones as director of International Relations Dept., James Parrott executive assistant to the president, David Melman assistant to the president), hiring freeze, opposition to use of temporary foreign workers; minutes of fifth meeting of GEB, October 7-13, 1987; Mazur report to GEB, February 1988; Report of the Benefit Funds Dept. to the GEB, February 2, 1988; Executive Committee Meeting Agenda, Dec. 15, 1987; 1988 Major Market Negotiations Task Forces; confidential Policy Decisions Arrived at 2/88 GEB Meeting
  - ILGWU General Executive Board (GEB), October, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    Opening remarks by Mazur
  - ILGWU GEB minutes, October, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    Summary of decisions made at October General Executive Board meeting
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous files
  - AFL-CIO Director's Report, February 17, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Chishti, Muzaffar, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Coia, Arthur A., 1995 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Clinton/Commerce Department/Workplace of the Future Conference, Chicago, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Clinton/Commerce Department/Workplace of the Future Conference, Chicago, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - 104th Congress-grassroots legislative and political activities, 1995 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Mazur, Jay, talk at Harvard University, April 19, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Donahue, Tom, file (Sweeney), 1995 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Dyson, John, Deputy Mayor of Finance, meeting, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Evolution of Work, March 30, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Future of U.S. Workplace/Evolution of Work, Q&A, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - NYC,Giuliani Administration/Economic Development Commission, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - NYC, Giuliani/Washington, Fashion Industry article, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - NYC, Giuliani Administration/meetings/NYC Economic Development Corporation (EDC)/ Lifflander, Clay, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - NYC, Giuliani Administration/privitization, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Jay Mazur notes, January-June, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Sturz, Herbert, April 8, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Jay Mazur testimony, Dunlop Commission, July 25, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Townsend, Alair, November 27, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Trade/Starobin-Dubrow, 1991-1994 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Trade/Current, 1988-1999 (Box 38, Folder 21)